Schwyn Francis



schwynf@gmail.com



(630) 903-9996



linkedin.com/in/schwyn-francis-5a47a9199



https://www.schwynfrancis.com/

Summary

Experienced professional with a demonstrated history of client facing work and completing team projects. 2+ years of JavaScript experience. On top of my Bachelors Degree, I recently earned a Full Stack Web Development certificate from the University of Arizona. I am currently focused on utilizing my web development skills to help a business grow. Main focus is MERN stack (MongoDB, Express.js, React.js, Node.js).

Experience



Environmental Health Specialist

Maricopa County Environmental Services

Sep 2016 - Present (4 years 6 months +)

- EHS inspector for the Aquatics Health & Safety Department.
- Regulate Maricopa County Environmental Health Code.
- Conduct public & semi-public swimming pool construction inspections and manage over 700 permits for routine compliance.
- Train new employees by providing important information and resources as part of training procedures.
- 90% of work is remote.

Laboratory Technician III

Doctor's Data, Inc.

Mar 2014 - Jun 2016 (2 years 4 months)

- Conducted chemical analyses on body fluids, such as blood or urine, using LC/MS systems.
- Worked with Agilent MassHunter Workstation, Orchard Harvest and Labvantage for instrument control, data acquisition, qualitative and quantitative data analysis, and reporting.
- Provided support to the research and development staff in the Chromatography Department.
- Team Lead by performing supervisor duties when supervisor is absent or out of office.

Education



Illinois State University

Bachelor of Science - BS, Biology/Biological Sciences, General 2011 - 2013

Licenses & Certifications



Full Stack Web Development - University of Arizona

Registered Environmental Health Specialist/Registered Sanitarian (REHSRS) -

Arizona Department of Health Services

Issued Jan 2021 - Expires Dec 2021

Skills

JavaScript • jQuery • MySQL • MongoDB • Node.js • Express.js • GitHub • AngularJS • React.js • C#

Honors & Awards

New Employee Of The Year - Maricopa County Environmental Services
Aug 2017
performance-driven